ANNA BOERI

annaboeri@gmail.com | Los Angeles, CA 90025 | 443-465-3318 | github.com/annaboeri

WEB DEVELOPER

I am a Web Developer with previous experience in Teaching and Tech Recruiting. Currently, I'm working with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), and the MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js). Most recently, I built an app called GLOBALink using Node.js, Express, and React, which allows users to explore random cities in the world. The app pulls data from multiple APIs, including Twitter, Google Maps, OpenWeatherMap, and RESTCountries, and integrates Socket.io to allow users to chat in real time with people from around the world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Databases: MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, PostgreSQL,

Bootstrap, React Active Record

Back-End: Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails **Methodologies:** MVC, OOP, REST, Agile **APIs:** socket.io, IBM Watson Natural Language

Understanding, Google Maps, Google Places, Twitter,

Version Control: Git, GitHub OpenWeatherMap, RESTCountries

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT STUDENT, GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Santa Monica, CA (1/2018 – 4/2018)

• Designed, developed, and deployed full-stack web applications using various technologies, including JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML5, and CSS3.

PROJECTS:

- **GLOBALink:** I created a Node.js, Express, and MongoDB Single Page App using React on the front end. The app allows users to learn about cities around the world by generating a random world city and displaying relevant information about that city. There is also a chat feature utilizing socket.io to allow users to chat in real time with other users from around the globe.
- **Etch App**: I worked with three other developers to create a Node.js app using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, and MongoDB. The app integrates IBM Watson's Natural Language Understanding API to analyze the emotions in text, helping users to better understand the emotions they are conveying through their language.
- **HikeLA App**: I built a Ruby on Rails app with PostgreSQL that allows users to browse hikes in the LA area, add hikes they've completed to their profile, and review hikes they've been on.
- **Connect 4 Game:** I built a two-player Connect 4-style game using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TEACHER, LES ENFANTS PRESCHOOL, Santa Monica, CA (2/2017 – 1/2018)

• Developed and implemented lesson plans to foster the physical, social, and emotional development of 2 and 3 year olds.

TEACHER, EARLY YEARS PRESCHOOL, Arlington, VA (5/2014 – 08/2016)

• Developed and implemented lesson plans to foster the physical, social, and emotional development of 3-4 year olds and provided support, guidance, and feedback to my Assistant Teacher as necessary.

STAFF RECRUITER, THE BULLER GROUP, LLC, Reston, VA (2/2013 - 5/2014)

• Responsible for sourcing and recruiting technical candidates, conducting hiring events with clients, and managing applicant pool.

TALENT ACQUISITION MANAGER, PCN STRATEGIES, Washington, D.C. (8/2012 - 02/2013)

• Responsible for full life cycle recruiting of technical candidates for positions with various clients.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY / Web Development Immersive / Santa Monica, CA (01/2018 – 04/2018)

STANFORD UNIVERSITY / B.A. in Psychology / *Stanford, CA* (09/2008 – 06/2012)

- 3.6 GPA, Member of the Varsity Women's Lacrosse Team, 2008 2012
- Three-time MPSF Women's Lacrosse All-Academic Selection, 2010 2012
- Academic Honor Roll, Intercollegiate Women's Lacrosse Coaches Association, 2012